Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Well. if this is it.
old boy.
I hope you don't mind if I
go out speaking the King's.
By all means.
Captain.
There's a special rung in hell reserved
for people who waste good Scotch.
Seeing as I may be rapping
on the door momentarily.
I must say.
damn good stuff. sir.
Now. about this pickle
we find ourselves in.
It would appear there's only
one thing left for you to do.
And what would that be?
Stiglitz.
Say auf Wiedersehen
to your Nazi balls.
You outside.
Who are you?
British? American?
What?
We're American.
What are you?
I'm a German. you idiot.
Speak English
pretty good for a German.
I agree.
So let's talk.
Okay. talk.
I'm a father.
My baby was born today.
In Frankfurt.
Five hours ago.
His name is Max.
We were in here drinking. celebrating.
They're the ones that came in shooting
and killing. It's not my fault!
Okay!
It wasn't your fault.
What's your name.
soldier?
Wilhelm.
Now. is there anybody alive
on our side?
No.
I'm alive!
Who's that?
Is the girl
on your side?
Which girl?
Who do you think?
Von Hammersmark.
Yeah. she's ours.
Is she okay?
Wilhelm!
She's been shot.
But she's alive.
Okay. Wilhelm.
What do you say
we make us a deal?
What's your name?
Aldo.
Okay. Wilhelm.
here's my deal.
You let me and one of my men come
down there and take the girl away.
No guns. No guns me.
no guns you.
And we take the girl and leave.
It's that simple. Willi.
You go your way.
we go ours.
And little Max gets to grow up
playing catch with his daddy.
So what do you say. Willi?
We got us a deal?
Aldo.
I'm here. Willi.
I want to trust you.
But...
But how can I?
What choice you got.
son?
Okay. okay.
Aldo.
I'm going to trust you.
Come down.
Hey. Willi. what's with the machine
gun? I thought we had us a deal?
We still have a deal.
Now. get the girl and go.
Not so fast.
We only got a deal.
we trust each other.
And a Mexican standoff
ain't trust.
You need guns on me for it
to be a Mexican standoff.
You got guns on us.
You decide to shoot. we're dead.
Up top. they got grenades.
They drop them down here. you're dead.
That's a Mexican standoff.
and that was not the deal.
No trust.
no deal.
All right. Aldo.
Fine.
Just take that fucking traitor.
and get her out of my sight.
Not so goddamn fast. doc.
Tell him to go play with his dogs.
Before we yank that slug out you.
you need to answer a few questions.
Few questions
about what?
About I got three men
dead back there.
Why don't you try telling us
what the fuck happened?
The British officer blew his German
act and the Gestapo major saw it.
Before we get into
who shot John.
why'd you invite my men to a rendezvous
in a basement with a bunch of Nazis?
I can see since you didn't
see what happened inside.
that the Nazis being there
must look odd.
Yeah. we got a word for
that kind of odd in English.
It's called suspicious.
Everybody needs
to calm down.
You're letting your imagination
get the better of you.
You met the sergeant
yourself. Willi.
You remember him.
don't you?
Yeah. I remember him.
His wife had a baby tonight.
He had just become a...
He had just become
a father!
His commanding officer gave him and
his mates the night off to celebrate.
The Germans being there was either a
trap set by me or a tragic coincidence.
It couldn't be both.
How'd the shooting start?
The Englishman
gave himself away.
How'd he do that?
He ordered three glasses.
We order three glasses.
That's the German three.
The other looks odd.
Germans would
and did notice it.
Okay. let's pretend
there were no Germans
and everything went exactly
the way it was supposed to.
What was the next step?
Tuxedos.
To get them into the premiere
wearing military uniforms
with all the military there
would've been suicide.
But going as members
of the German film industry.
they wear tuxedos and fit
in with everybody else.
I arranged for the tailor
to fit three tuxedos tonight.
How'd you intend to get them
in that premiere?
Hand me my purse.
Lieutenant Hicox
was going as my escort.
The other two were going as a
German cameraman and his assistant.
You still get us
in that premiere?
You speak German better
than your friends? No.
Have I been shot? Yes!
I don't see me tripping the light
fantastique up a red carpet anytime soon.
Least of all.
by tomorrow night.
However. there's something
you don't know.
There've been two recent
developments regarding Operation Kino.
One. the venue has been changed from
The Ritz to a much smaller venue.
Enormous change at the last minute?
That's not very Germatic.
Why the hell is Goebbels
doing stuff so damn peculiar?
It probably has something to
do with the second development.
Which is?
Der Fuhrer is attending
the premiere.
Fuck a duck!
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking getting a whack
at planting old Uncle Adolf
makes this horse
a different color.
What is that
supposed to mean?
It means you getting us
in that premiere.
I'm probably going
to end up losing this leg.
Bye-bye. acting career.
Fun while it lasted.
How do you expect me
to walk the red carpet?
Doggy doc's going to dig
that slug out your gam.
He's going to wrap it up
in a cast.
and you got a good how-l-broke-my-leg-
mountain-climbing story.
That's German. ain't it?
You all like climbing mountains. don't you?
I don't. I like smoking. drinking
and ordering in restaurants.
But I see your point.
We fill you up with morphine
till it's coming out your ears
and just limp your little
ass up that reuge carpet.
I know this is a silly
question before I ask it.
but can you Americans speak
any other language than English?
We both speak
a little Italian.
With an atrocious accent.
no doubt.
But that doesn't exactly
kill us in the crib.
Germans don't have
a good ear for Italian.
So you mumble Italian and brazen
through it. Is that the plan?
That's about it.
That sounds good.
It sounds like shit. What else
are we going to do? Go home?
No. that sounds good.
If you don't blow it. with that.
I can get you in the building.
Who does what?
Well. I speak the most
Italian. so I'll be your escort.
Donowitz speaks second most. so
he'll be your Italian cameraman.
Omar. third most.
He'll be Donny's assistant.
I don't speak Italian.
Like I said. third best. Just
keep your fucking mouth shut.
In fact. why don't you
start practicing right now?
Yes.
Gorlomi?
Gorlomi.
Antonio Margheriti.
Margheriti.
Dominick Decocco.
What's that
American expression?
"If the shoe fits.
you must wear it."
Fucking shithead.
Faggot fuck. Fuck you!
Bunch of shithead fuck.
Fuck you. too!
Goddamn Nazi farts. sons of bitches!
Get your hands off me.
You fucking bratwurst-smelling...
Goddamn you! Get off!
Hmm.
You Jerry-banging.
Limburg-smelling...
As Stanley said
to Livingstone.
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
I presume?
Hans Landa.
You've had
a nice long run. Aldo.
Alas. you're now
in the hands of the SS.
My hands to be exact.
And they've been waiting
a long time to touch you.
Caught you flinching.
Touch me again. Kraut-burger.
Utivich?
Is that you.
Lieutenant?
Yeah.
Do you know
what happened to Donny?
Omar?
The woman?
No. I do not.
Tell me. Aldo. if I were
sitting where you're sitting.
would you
show me mercy?
Nope.
What is that English
expression about shoes and feet?
"Looks like the shoe is on the other foot."
- Yeah. I was just thinking that.
So you're Aldo the Apache.
So you're The Jew Hunter.
I'm a detective.
A damn good detective.
Finding people
is my specialty.
so naturally. I worked for
the Nazis finding people.
And. yes. some of them were Jews.
But Jew Hunter?
Just a name that stuck.
Well. you do have to
admit. it is catchy.
Do you control the nicknames
your enemies bestow on you?
Aldo the Apache
and the Little Man?
What do you mean
the Little Man?
Germans' nickname for you.
The Germans' nickname for me
is the Little Man?
And as if to make my point. I'm a little
surprised how tall you were in real life.
I mean. you're a little fellow.
but not circus-midget little.
as your reputation
would suggest.
Where's my men?
Where's
Bridget von Hammersmark?
Well. let's just say.
she got what she deserved.
And when you purchase friends
like Bridget von Hammersmark.
you get what you pay for.
Now as far as your paesanos.
Sergeant Donowitz and Private Omar...
How you know our names?
Lieutenant Aldo.
if you don't think
I wouldn't interrogate
every single one of your
swastika-marked survivors.
we simply aren't operating on the
level of mutual respect I assumed.
No. I guess not.
Well. back to the whereabouts
of your two Italian saboteurs.
As of this moment.
both Omar and Donowitz should be sitting
in the very seats we left them in.
Double-zero 23 and
double-zero 24. if my memory serves.
Explosives still around their
ankles. still ready to explode.
And your mission. some
would call a terrorist plot.
as of this moment.
is still a go.
That's a pretty exciting story.
What's next? Eliza on Ice?
However.
all I have to do is pick up
this phone right here.
inform the cinema.
and your plan is kaput.
If they're still here. and if they're
still alive. and that's one big if.
there ain't no way you're
going to take them boys
without setting off
them bombs.
I have no doubt.
And. yes. some Germans will die.
Yes. it will ruin the evening.
And. yes. Goebbels will be
very. very. very mad at you
for what you've done
to his big night.
But you won't get Hitler.
you won't get Goebbels.
you won't get Goring.
and you won't get Bormann.
And you need all four
to end the war.
But if I don't pick up
this phone right here.
you may very well
get all four.
And if you get all four.
you end the war
tonight.
So. gentlemen.
let's discuss the prospect
of ending the war tonight.
So. the way I see it.
since Hitler's death or possible
rescue rests solely on my reaction.
if I do nothing.
it's as if I'm causing his
death even more than yourselves.
Wouldn't you agree?
I guess so.
How about you.
Utivich?
I guess so. too.
Gentlemen.
I have no intention
of killing Hitler and killing Goebbels
and killing Goring and killing Bormann.
not to mention winning the war
single-handedly for the Allies.
only later to find myself
standing before a Jewish tribunal.
If you want to win
the war tonight.
we have to make a deal.
What kind of deal?
The kind you wouldn't
have the authority to make.
However. I'm sure this mission
of yours has a commanding officer.
A general.
I'm betting for...
OSS would be my guess.
That's a bingo!
Is that the way you say it?
"That's a bingo."
You just say. "Bingo."
Bingo! How fun.
But I digress. Where were we?
Yeah! Make a deal.
Over there is a very capable
two-way radio and sitting behind it
is a more than capable
radio operator named Hermann.
Get me someone on the
other end of that radio
with the power of the pen
to authorize my.
let's call it. the terms
of my conditional surrender.
If that tastes better
going down.
You know.
where I'm from...
Yeah?
Where is that exactly?
Maynardville.
Tennessee.
I've done my share
of bootlegging.
Up there. if you engage in what the
federal government calls illegal activity.
but what we call just a man trying
to make a living for his family
selling moonshine liquor. it
behooves oneself to keep his wits.
Long story short. we hear
a story too good to be true.
it ain't.
Sitting in your chair.
I would probably say the same thing.
and 999. 999 times out of a million.
you would be correct.
But in the pages of history.
every once in a while.
fate reaches out
and extends its hand.
What shall
the history books read?
I implore you.
We must destroy that tower.
Sarge. that tower...
The tower stands!
Psst! Psst!
So when the military
history of this night is written.
it will be recorded that I
was part of Operation Kino
from the very beginning
as a double agent.
Anything I've done in
my guise as an SS Colonel
was sanctioned by the OSS
as a necessary evil
to establish my cover
with the Germans.
And it was my placement of
Lieutenant Raine's dynamite
in Hitler and Goebbels' opera
box that assured their demise.
By the way. that last
part is actually true.
I want my full military pension
and benefits under my proper rank.
I want to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honor
for my invaluable assistance in
the toppling of the Third Reich.
In fact. I want all the
members of Operation Kino
to receive the
Congressional Medal of Honor.
Full citizenship for myself.
Well. that goes without saying.
And I would like
the United States of America
to purchase property for me
on Nantucket Island
as a reward for all the
countless lives I've saved
by bringing the tyranny of
the National Socialist Party
to a swifter-than-imagined end.
Do you have all that. sir?
I look forward to seeing you
face to face as well. sir.
Lieutenant Raine?
Right here.
Yes. sir.
Colonel Landa will put you and
Private Utivich in a truck as prisoners.
Then he and his radio operator will
get in the truck and drive to our lines.
Upon crossing our lines. Colonel Landa
and his man will surrender to you.
You will then take over
driving of the truck
and bring them straight to me for
debriefing. Is that clear. Lieutenant?
Yes. sir.
Over and out.
When I kill that guy. you got
30 feet to get to that guard.
Can you do it?
I have to.
Champagne?
Who wants to send
a message to Germany?
I have a message
for Germany.
That you are
all going to die.
And I want you to look deep into the
face of the Jew who's going to do it!
Marcel. burn it down.
Oui. Shosanna.
My name
is Shosanna Dreyfus.
and this is the face
of Jewish vengeance.
Hermann.
uncuff them.
I'm officially surrendering myself
over to you. Lieutenant Raine.
We're your prisoners.
How about my knife?
Thank you very much.
Colonel.
Utivich. cuff the Colonel's
hands behind his back.
Is that really
necessary?
I'm a slave
to appearances.
Scalp Hermann.
Are you mad?
What have you done?
I made a deal with your
general for that man's life!
Yeah. they made that deal. But they don't
give a fuck about him. They need you.
You'll be shot for this!
Nah. I don't think so. More like
chewed out. I've been chewed out before.
You know. Utivich and myself heard
that deal you made with the brass.
End the war tonight?
I'd make that deal.
How about you. Utivich?
You make that deal?
I'd make that deal.
I don't blame you.
Damn good deal.
And that pretty little nest
you feathered for yourself.
Well. if you're willing to
barbecue the whole High Command.
I suppose that's worth
certain considerations.
But I do have
one question.
When you get to your little
place on Nantucket Island.
I imagine you are going to take off that
handsome-looking SS uniform of yours.
Ain't you?
That's what I thought.
Now. that I can't abide.
How about you. Utivich.
can you abide it?
Not one damn bit. sir.
I mean.
if I had my way.
you'd wear that goddamn uniform for
the rest of your pecker-sucking life.
But I'm aware
that ain't practical.
I mean. at some point.
you're going to have to take it off.
So.
I'm going to give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know something.
Utivich?
I think this just might be
my masterpiece.
Subtitles by LeapinLar
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-